Finding Aid for the Vanderbilt Aid Society
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Vanderbilt Aid Society
2007
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0471
2.09 linear feet
Scope and Content Note
This small collection consists of 0.63 linear feet of materials relating to the founding of the Vanderbilt Aid Society, or the Ladies Aid Society for the Students of Vanderbilt University as it was called at the beginning. The collection contains correspondence, brief historical notes about the Society by various people connected with it, and the records that have been kept concerning the Treasurers’ reports and the loan fund reports, as well as the minutes from the meetings, 1894 - 1950.
- Correspondence—October14, 1932 - 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1945 - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1954 - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Report of Chancellor Kirkland; Constitution of the Ladies’ Aid Society; Full report and history with testimonials from students aided; Constitution and By-Laws (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Constitution and By-Laws and Revisions to, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Constitution and By-Laws, 1967 (Revised) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Financial records, 1894-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Vanderbilt Aid Loan Fund Register, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Vanderbilt Aid Loan Fund Reports, May 1, 1937 - Nov. 1, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Vanderbilt Aid Loan Fund Reports, May 1, 1940 - June 30, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Vanderbilt Aid Loan Fund Reports, July 1, 1950 - June 30, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Vanderbilt Aid Loan Fund Reports, July 1, 1959 - February 28, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Report on the Vanderbilt Loan Funds, June 30, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence—Vanderbilt Aid Loan Fund, 1960, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Reports of the Treasurer, October 1937 - May 1, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Reports of the Treasurer, 1943 - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- List of Students who received aid, 1935 - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Membership List, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- List of homes in which the Vanderbilt Aid Society has met from, 1894-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Invitations to meetings, 1961, 1962, 1963; List of hostesses for Vanderbilt Aid Tea (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Notice of yearly meeting, April 27, 1970; May 7, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Letter mailed to friends on the occasion of the 50th Anniversary of the Founding of the Vanderbilt Aid Society; Handwritten history (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Brief History (1921) by Mrs. E. W. Foster, President of the Ladies’ Aid Society of Vanderbilt; “Ladies Aid Society” in History of Vanderbilt by Edwin Mims (1946), pp. 253 - 254 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tributes to Mrs. Thomas J. Tyne; Mrs. Claude Waller given by Cornelia Keeble, October 20, 1943; Resignation of Mrs. Mary T. Orr (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Article by Aileen Bishop (historian) “ The Funding of the Vanderbilt Aid Society”, April 6, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- “67 Years of Service: The Vanderbilt Aid” photocopy of an article from Vanderbilt Alumnus, March-April, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Articles—“Tea and Money” Vanderbilt Alumnus/ Summer 1977, v.62, n.4, p. 40; “ Aid Society Marks 113th year with Talk on its History” Vanderbilt Register, May 3, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Application for Loan form (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Minutes of the Vanderbilt Aid Society, 1894-1911 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Minutes of the Vanderbilt Aid Society, May 26, 1911 - 1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minutes of the Vanderbilt Aid Society, May 26, 1927 - May 10, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)